hey guys this is such a fun looking
problem we have two circles with a
radius of 5 m and then we have a square
stuck inside here and it wants us to
find the area of this square if you want
to try this on your own pause it right
now because I'm going to solve it in 3 2
1 first step I want to label the sides
of this Square X so the area we're going
to solve for is going to be X2 and let's
stick that right over here next let's
draw another radius from the center of
this circle to the intersection point
right here and let's draw another radius
from this point here to this tangent
point and that's going to be at right
angles each of these blue lines are both
radi of the circle so they're both going
to have a length of 5 Metter and let's
extend this line right here parallel to
this so that this will also be a right
angle so with this setup this red
portion of the line right here is the
same thing as the height of this Square
so it will also have a length of X and
since this whole thing has a length of
five this remaining blue portion will be
5 - x and then let's call this green
line Y we now have a right triangle
right here so so we can use a 2 + B2 =
c^2 we can do 5 - x^2 + y^2 = 5^ 2 5 -
x^2 is 5 - x * 5 - x which gives us 25 -
10 x + x^2 and then we still have the +
y^ 2 and it'll be equal to 5^2 which is
25 and then we can subtract 25 from both
sides and we can also subtract the rest
of the stuff from both sides on the left
hand side we only have y^2 and on the
right hand side we have 10 x - x^2 after
we square root both both sides we have y
is equal to the < TK 10x - x^2 and now
we can clean things up a little bit
let's scoot this over here and let's
duplicate the Y over here now this
distance is going to be equal to this
distance so we know that y + x + y is
equal to 5 + 5 and we can clean this up
a little bit y + y is 2 Y and 5 + 5 is
10 and now we know that Y is equal to
the < TK of 10x - x^2 so in the place of
this y we can plug in < TK of 10x - x 2
and now we just got to solve for x we
can subtract X from both sides that'll
give us 2 * the < TK of 10x - x^2 is
equal to 10 - x and then we can square
both sides of the equation this Square
will distribute to both of these so we
have 2 squar and then we have this stuff
squared 2^ 2 is equal to 4 and this
square root and this Square are going to
cancel each other out and then 10 - x^2
means this times this and it ends up
being 100 - 20x + x^2 then we can
distribute this 4 it'll give us 40x -
4x^2 and then we can subtract this stuff
from both sides so we can set it all
equal to zero let's bring down the 100
-2X - 4x is - 60x and x^2 + 4x^2 is 5
x^2 all three of these coefficients are
divisible by 5 so let's do that we end
up with 0 = 20 - 12x + x^2 and then we
can Factor this we need two numbers that
add to -12 and multiply to POS 20 well
that's going to be -10 and -2 so we have
X x - 10 * x - 2 = 0 that means that
either this equals 0 or this equals 0 so
for x - 10al 0 we can add 10 to both
sides and we get xal 10 what we can see
right here since the radius is five
there's no way that X is 10 so this is
not a valid solution and then for x - 2
= 0 we can add two to both sides and we
get x = 2 this one is a valid solution
so now that we know x = 2 the area of
our square is going to be equal to 2^2
which is 4 let's give it a label of
meters squared and put a box around it
how exciting